[Music]
hello my name is Ian ktic and I'm a
product manager in business Central
product team and I want to welcome you
to the business Central launch event I'm
so super excited to tell you about
what's new in data verse and damic 365
apps
integration this session's agenda covers
following five improvements that we are
introducing in 2023 release Wave 2 and
some that you might have missed as they
have been introduced in July as part of
the minor updates for 2023 release Wave
1 so we'll talk about how to connect and
integrate business Central with data ver
and Dynamics a65 applic apption in
configurations involving multiple
environments multiple companies and
different base currencies we'll also
walk through how users can synchronize
even more data out of the box through
additional Fields mapping uh without a
need for a developer and how to better
control your data synchronization and
enable virtual tables so let's
dig with 2023 release wave two you can
now unlock scenarios where multiple
companies from multiple business Central
environments must access data in the
same datae environments this enables
Partners to build new experiences when
working in more than one company
environment or base
currency when you enable multi company
synchronization following things happen
you get warned of the changes that will
happen to integration filters and some
recommendations for selected integration
Table mappings after that the company
filters get removed on user and team own
tables such as account or cont contact
tables sales quotes order sales quotes
and Order synchronization becomes more
restrictive with respect to company
filters users now must pick company in
Dynamics 365 uh sales to specify the
business Central company that will
process a particular document this is to
avoid companies companies hijacking each
other's
documents and the last thing this
setting has no effect uh on the tables
that are organization owned in data such
as currency
table users can now pick and change uh
the default business Central environment
and company that will be used to open
coupled records from Dynamics 365 for
sales in business
Central this information is preserved as
a per user setting but this can be
changed anytime by the user this is
mainly to avoid users picking a business
Central company every time they need to
open a coupled record in Dynamics 365 or
sales or data
ver documents such as sales quotes or
orders requires users to pick Target
business Central invironment and company
that will process a specific document as
mentioned for documents company filters
are now stricter on company filtering
meaning sales quotes and orders without
explicit company Define will no longer
show up in the list of sales quotes and
orders that you can synchronize with a
particular business Central company
more complex configurations of
synchronizing data to a central data ver
or Dynamics 365 sales uh environment are
also supported it's good to know that
multi environment and multi- compan
synchronization Works across uh act
Azure active directory tenants as long
as you are synchronizing data to a
central data verse or Dynamics a65 for
sales
deployment if you are dealing with many
companies consider consolidating data
you want to synchronize in one master
data company in business Central and
then you use Master data management
capabilities of business Central to
synchronize Master data between business
Central companies and after that
integrate such uh Master data company
con that contains the Consolidated
Master data from Business Center
companies with a central data verse or
dynamic 365 sales deployment the result
of this approach will be more
performance synchronization and less
chance of hitting the service protection
limits on this data ver side it is also
very important to keep local data to
keep local data privacy and data storage
requirements in mind as you want to make
sure that data remains within the priv
Privacy boundaries when you're doing
synchronization you could ask but
doesn't synchronizing multiple
environments and Company necessarily
mean necessarily require dealing with
multiple currencies well yes when
integrating with Dynamics 365 or sales
or just data ver in environments with
there's Central
deployment of those apps and where you
are serving multiple markets it's
important that the integration to
business Central can accommodate for
differences in local and based
transaction currencies between those two
systems integration now ensures seamless
synchronization when multiple currencies
are involved so when a data verse based
currency and business Central local
currencies are different the following
things happen the only prerequisite that
you uh that you have is having data ver
based currency set up as a regular
currency in business Central with at
least one exchange rate in order to
enable connection otherwise you won't be
able to connect because the integration
needs to know about this uh about this
non-local uh base currency that exists
in in
datae then when you connect to datae
business centrals local currencies is
added to the list of currencies in data
verse
automatically integration converts
monetary amounts on the Fly this means
when converting amounts from business
Central local currency the amounts
synchronized with a business Central
local currency in one of the additional
or inserted on non- based currencies in
data ver on the other way when
converting amounts from uh data ver
based transaction currency amounts are
converted to business Central local
currency based on the latest exchange
rate synchronized from business
Central companies often customize their
integration between business Central and
data verse to fit their specific
business needs to make that easier to do
without the help of a developer we made
more Fields available for mapping in our
standard integration table mappings so
customer vendor contact salesperson and
opportunity integration field mappings
now have additional Fields available for
you to map the these additional fields
are disabled by default however in order
to use them you simply open integration
field mapping page choose the direction
and enable them turning off event based
synchronization for specific integration
table mappings can give you a greater
control over the flow of data between
business Central and data uh for example
you can reduce the risk of the data
errors inconsistencies and improve the
overall quality and reliability of the
data additionally opting out of event
based synchronization can speed up
performance by reducing the number of
synchronization events that business
Central needs to process the default
settings for the event-based
synchronization stay unchanged to avoid
disrupting uh existing
Integrations for some time uh we we've
been talking about virtual tables and
data synchronization as complimentary
integration Technologies and we'll
continue to invest in both Technologies
together to provide even more
value uh avoiding duplicate data entry
is one of the key value propositions for
integrating business Central with datae
and enabling virtual tables makes more
data available between business Central
and datae which enriches Integrations
without additional
customizations when there's overlapping
data in data verse or Dynamics 365
application such as
sales your choice should be data
synchronization and when that's not the
case the virtual table will offer
integration customization with less
effort so now when you enable and
connect to data verse U using assisted
setup you are now able to make specific
virtual tables visible already during
the setup this can be done for a single
table or in bul for multiple
tables to make additional virtual tables
available uh you can later on access the
list of the data ver available tables
from the connection set setup page as
well now that we are done with the
technical improvements it's also good to
know as many of you have asked us that
the commercial blockers for integrating
various Dynamic 365 apps have been
removed earlier this year we've
announced a set of attached licenses for
business Central premium license and for
Enterprise versions of sales customer
service and field service making you
more competitive when pricing an
integration project make sure to check
out the details below on the partner
portal on on the following
links and now let's see all of the above
in action in one short demo to prepare
for this demo I've already connected
Kronos us to the Kronos HQ data ver
environment and I've installed virtual
tables app uh to that
environment as you can see that both
sales and data ver connection setup are
enabled in Kronos
us let's go and uh switch to Kronos
de I picked the environment and side in
as an administrator and enable
synchronization and virtual tables just
so we don't have to go through those
steps even though I want to connect
without full sync as there's obviously
already data in data ver environments
let's continue let's click next to see
the sync recommendations
anyway so let's check the
synchronization
recommendation what you can see in here
there are two types of
recommendation one other thing to notice
is that there is a sort of a new type of
recommendation that is called review
coupling criteria where for some simple
tables like payment terms or currencies
we can automatically recommend coupling
criteria so users don't need to do and
review them or set them up manually as
you can see here for payment terms we
only have one field so it's obvious
which field we will use for for coupling
criteria for master data such as contact
customer or vendors business Central
recommends full synchronization as
current integration table filters don't
catch data already synced from tronus us
you will Al also notice there's a multic
company sync enabled column that has
been added so let's try to
toggle multic company synchronization
enabled so there's a new action that
says uh toggle multic company
synchronization you got a confirmation
if you want to proceed and
then you'll also get informed about
filters uh being changed and another
warning comes up which explain things in
details and let's click okay and now
with the with the filters uh removed
after we enabled the multic company
synchronization some data that is
already
synchronized for example let's click on
contacts
is actually available and the
recommendation changes from Full
synchronization to selecting coupling
criteria and we if we would want to go
and uh do that we could go there select
the coupling criteria and repeat this
for every integration table mapping that
we want to do but we'll do that later uh
in the demo so let's flip this back and
just to just proceed with
this yes I want to do
that okay
let's click okay here and let's go back
and let's turn off uh synchronization
click
next now that we are not doing initial
synchronization and as I said in the
beginning the virtual table setup was
enabled we can actually go and review
and enable virtual tables right from The
Wizard when I click review and enable
virtual tables available virtual table
Pages opens up so let's make sales
shipment and lines virtual tables
visible right from
here uh let me find sales shipment and
sales shipment line and let's uh
enable while this is completed in the
background we can simply go ahead and
click finish in the
Wizard okay and one other thing to do
what we can do in here we can also go
and enable
a connection to dyamic 365 for sales
let's just go ahead and enable
that so what you can see is we've
enabled data verse sales connection made
virtual tables visible directly from
business Central what you may notice
also is there were no complaints about
local currency being different from the
data verse base currency we can actually
go ahead and check that in general
ledger uh setup for this company you can
see there's a euro currency in
here so let's go and actually integrate
a few things in the multic company
scenario to do that I will open
integration table
mappings and just go and couple my
accounts as we saw in the warning the
recommendation if I were to go and
enable
this and say yes
but you can see from the warning the
recommendation in here is to change the
integration direction from B directional
sync to from integration table mapping
and to do this we need to have some
field set set to pick the data from from
data verse so let's go and do that let's
turn this
off and if we go to mapping Open Fields
but you can see a lot of our fields are
B directional let's go ahead and edit
list what I want to do is I do want to
map the number to the account number
that we have in there so what you see in
here this is one of these additional
fields that are disabled that are part
of the outof the Box field mappings that
come disabled by default but you can of
course go ahead and enable them the
things that I don't want to integrate
for the demo purposes just let me just
go ahead and disable couple of these
things and of course I don't want a
currency
code and what I'll do I will say I want
the name to come from integration
table and the website for
example okay that sets us up right now
we can actually go ahead and change the
direction of the integration table to
from integration table mapping and then
go ahead and enable multic company
synchronization okay and the last thing
I need to do is I will want I would want
to run my match best
coupling let's say yes let's expand this
and let's go and say I want to do
this like
this I'll just say let's do this
cing so let's let's go
to let's go to one of the
customers we should actually have them
coupled already let's go and try to open
that customer in say 65 for
sales and the thing that you can hear
see in here is this uh new button uh
that allows each user to set up a
default uh connection so I can go and
click choose def default business
Central connection and in here for
example I will
pick uh
Cronus I will pick
chromsde as the one that I want save and
close and then uh when I want to open a
uh coupled uh customer or coupled
account when I click open in business
Central it should actually go ahead and
take me to uh this other environment
that I have integrated this is uh
D so let's also see the sales
[Music]
orders and let's designate one company
that has been integrated to pick up this
particular sales order let's say that
this particular one is going to be
picked up by cronis De uh save
that oh I do need to pick the potential
customer let's make this a customer and
Save
I've enabled virtual tables so let's
have a look at the tables uh that I
actually have available in here and I
will just look for sale shipments so
both of these virtual tables that we've
decided to make visible uh through the
wizard are now available in here so this
concludes the demo uh in the demo you
saw uh how integration Works in multic
company and multi- environment setting
conversion of Base uh transaction
currency making virtual tables visible
and enablement of additional field
mappings this is of course not all that
has been improved in business Central
and data verse integration so if you
want to learn more about the
improvements in Virtual tables create
update delete events external business
events or or more make sure to watch the
session delivered uh by
Sandy as always if there are further
questions or you just want to be kept up
to date have a product suggestion
or want to connect to a product team in
in any way make sure to check the links
on this slide and with that and on
behalf of business Central product team
and myself I want to thank you for your
time and for joining this session make
sure to try out the improvements
presented and provide feedback to us
looking forward to seeing you or meeting
you in one of our next events thank
you